<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Dimitar Kostadinov</title>
    <link>https://dimvladkost.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dimvladkost.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dimvladkost.github.io/media/icon_hu4f0bd1eb3c8c76839337839d88f88ed3_346244_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://dimvladkost.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dendritic gated networks: A rapid and efficient learning rule for biological neural circuits</title>
      <link>https://dimvladkost.github.io/project/dgn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dimvladkost.github.io/project/dgn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project, we introduce a powerful new biologically plausible machine learning algorithm: the Dendritic Gated Network (DGN), a variant of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.1910.01526&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gated Linear Network&lt;/a&gt;.  DGNs combine dendritic ‘gating’ (whereby &amp;lsquo;interneurons&amp;rsquo; target dendrites to shape &amp;rsquo;neuronal&amp;rsquo; responses) with local learning rules to yield provably robust performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importantly,  DGNs  have  structural  and  functional  similarities  to cerebellar circuits, where (1) climbing fibers provide a well-defined feedback signal (&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-neuro-080317-061948&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Raymond and Medina, 2018&lt;/a&gt;), (2) the input-output transformation is relatively linear (&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1113/jphysiol.1980.sp013357&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Llinás and Sugimori, 1980&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1523/jneurosci.4507-05.2006&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Walter and Khodakhah, 2006&lt;/a&gt;), and (3) molecular layer interneurons could act as local gates on learning (&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.15-04-02777.1995&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Callaway et al., 1995&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.36246&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gaffield et al., 2018&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tins.2010.08.004&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jörntell et al., 2010&lt;/a&gt;). To make this link explicit, we have performed two-photon calcium imaging experiments of Purkinje cell dendrites and molecular layer interneurons in awake mice. With these recordings, we find  that single interneurons suppress activity in individual dendritic branches of Purkinje cells in vivo, validating a  key  feature  of  the  model. Thus, our theoretical and experimental results draw a specific link between learning in DGNs and the functional architecture of the cerebellum. The generality of the DGN architecture should also allow this algorithm to be implemented in a range of networks in the mammalian brain, including the neocortex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is a collaboration with researchers at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ucl.ac.uk/gatsby/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gatsby Computational Neuroscience Unit&lt;/a&gt; at UCL and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepmind.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Google DeepMind&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerebellar cell type classification</title>
      <link>https://dimvladkost.github.io/project/cell_type_id/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dimvladkost.github.io/project/cell_type_id/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are combining cell type-specific optogenetics, electrophysiology, and machine learning to develop methods to classify cerebellar neurons based on their unique functional identities. This project is a collaboration between several cerebellar labs using high-density extracellular electrophysiology probes in multiple species (mouse, rat, and macaque). Our aim is to provide a fully integrated open-source toolkit for automatic cell type classification of high-density recordings in the cerebellum that will greatly facilitate a circuit-wide understanding of the contribution of different cell types to cerebellar-dependent behaviours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- We are combining cell type-specific optogenetics, electrophysiology, and machine learning to develop methods to classify cerebellar neurons based on their unique functional identities. This project is a collaboration between several cerebellar labs ([Häusser Lab](http://www.dendrites.org), UCL; [Cohen Lab](https://gondabrain.biu.ac.il/en/node/268), Bar Ilan University; [Medina Lab](https://www.bcm.edu/people-search/javier-medina-26564), Baylor University; [Hull](https://www.neuro.duke.edu/research/faculty-labs/hull-lab) and [Lisberger](https://www.neuro.duke.edu/research/faculty-labs/lisberger-lab) Labs, Duke University) using high-density extracellular electrophysiology probes in multiple species (mouse, rat, and macaque). Our aim is to provide a fully integrated open-source toolkit for automatic cell type classification of high-density recordings in the cerebellum that will greatly facilitate a circuit-wide understanding of the contribution of different cell types to cerebellar-dependent behaviours.  --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transformation of Purkinje cell population codes in the cerebellar nuclei</title>
      <link>https://dimvladkost.github.io/project/pc_cbn_transform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dimvladkost.github.io/project/pc_cbn_transform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The interplay between Purkinje cells and nuclear cells has been a topic of debate in the cerebellar field for decades. While Purkinje cells are GABAergic, their effect on nuclear output may not be inhibitory, because nuclear neurons exhibit unique biophysical features that make them susceptible to &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/nature10732&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;entrainment by artificial stimulation of Purkinje cells&lt;/a&gt;. Whether this entrainment occurs under physiological conditions remains unknown, largely due to the difficulty of recording connected Purkinje cells and nuclear neurons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, we are seeking to settle this debate by making direct recordings of synaptically connected Purkinje cells and nuclear neurons using &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuropixels&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Neuropixels probes&lt;/a&gt;. This project is the primary PhD work of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/m-beau&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Maxime Beau&lt;/a&gt;, a PhD student in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dendrites.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Neural Computation Laboratory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerebellar learning, fast and slow</title>
      <link>https://dimvladkost.github.io/project/fast_slow_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dimvladkost.github.io/project/fast_slow_learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Climbing fiber (CF) inputs to cerebellar Purkinje cells (PCs) encode sensorimotor and reward-related instructive signals that are utilized to learn and refine goal-directed behaviors. However, it remains unclear how these instructive signals evolve during the acquisition and refinement phases of learning, whether they target the same PCs, and whether different brain-wide pathways drive functionally distinct populations of CFs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, we used 2-photon calcium imaging to record CF inputs to PCs chronically over weeks while head-fixed mice learned to perform a visuomotor integration task (slow learning). Once mice were experts, we probed fast, adaptive learning by altering the gain between object translation and wheel movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our results suggest that instructive CF signals define functionally distinct cerebellar regions: inputs to some cerebellar regions primarily receive sensorimotor instruction and mediates the slow acquisition of goal-directed behaviors, while inputs to other regions preferentially receive reward-related instruction that can guide fast adaptation to dynamic environmental contexts. We are exploring whether this regional functional specialization may result from the differential brain-wide circuits driving distinct populations of presynaptic olivary neurons.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
