<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resources | Dimitar Kostadinov</title>
    <link>https://dimvladkost.github.io/tag/resources/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dimvladkost.github.io/tag/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Resources</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dimvladkost.github.io/media/icon_hu4f0bd1eb3c8c76839337839d88f88ed3_346244_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://dimvladkost.github.io/tag/resources/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerebellar cell type classification</title>
      <link>https://dimvladkost.github.io/project/cell_type_id/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dimvladkost.github.io/project/cell_type_id/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are combining cell type-specific optogenetics, electrophysiology, and machine learning to develop methods to classify cerebellar neurons based on their unique functional identities. This project is a collaboration between several cerebellar labs using high-density extracellular electrophysiology probes in multiple species (mouse, rat, and macaque). Our aim is to provide a fully integrated open-source toolkit for automatic cell type classification of high-density recordings in the cerebellum that will greatly facilitate a circuit-wide understanding of the contribution of different cell types to cerebellar-dependent behaviours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- We are combining cell type-specific optogenetics, electrophysiology, and machine learning to develop methods to classify cerebellar neurons based on their unique functional identities. This project is a collaboration between several cerebellar labs ([Häusser Lab](http://www.dendrites.org), UCL; [Cohen Lab](https://gondabrain.biu.ac.il/en/node/268), Bar Ilan University; [Medina Lab](https://www.bcm.edu/people-search/javier-medina-26564), Baylor University; [Hull](https://www.neuro.duke.edu/research/faculty-labs/hull-lab) and [Lisberger](https://www.neuro.duke.edu/research/faculty-labs/lisberger-lab) Labs, Duke University) using high-density extracellular electrophysiology probes in multiple species (mouse, rat, and macaque). Our aim is to provide a fully integrated open-source toolkit for automatic cell type classification of high-density recordings in the cerebellum that will greatly facilitate a circuit-wide understanding of the contribution of different cell types to cerebellar-dependent behaviours.  --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neuropixels 2.0: A miniaturized high-density probe for stable, long-term brain recordings</title>
      <link>https://dimvladkost.github.io/publication/steinmetz2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dimvladkost.github.io/publication/steinmetz2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
